Inventory of Leslie Gottesman papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Leslie Gottesman papers
1935-2011
2015C5
Hoover Institution Archives
13 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes, 1 card file box (6.6 linear feet)
Correspondence, writings, pamphlets, bulletins, serial issues, other printed matter, audio and video recordings and transcripts of interviews, and slides relating to the history of Eritrea, including its political and social conditions as well as education. Used in part as research material for Leslie Gottesman's book, To Fight and Learn: The Praxis and Promise of Literacy in Eritrea’s War of Independence (Lawrenceville, New Jersey, 1998).
Gottesman, Leslie.
Access
The collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2014.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical note
Leslie "Les" Gottesman, an American teacher and writer, was born in Portland, Oregon in 1941. He attended Columbia University, receiving a B.A. in 1968 and an M. A. in 1969, and an Ed.D from the University of San Francisco in 1994 and a MFA from the California College of the Arts in 2011. He is a professor emeritus of English at Golden Gate University in San Francisco, where he taught for twenty eight years, as well as serving as the Dean of the School of Arts and Sciences from 1994 to 1996 and as Director of General Education from 2001 to 2007.
Gottesman's 1998 book, To Fight and Learn: The Praxis and Promise of Literacy in Eritrea's Independence War, published by Red Sea Press, was based on research done in Eritrea in 1993. His research continued during visits to Eritrea in 2000 and 2001.
In San Francisco, Gottesman writes poetry and, under the imprint Omerta Publications, publishes poetry chapbooks by himself and others.
Scope and Contents note
Include materials collected over nine years and three research trips to Eritrea in 1993, 2000, and 2001 relating to the history, political and social conditions, and education in Eritrea, such as correspondence, writings, pamphlets, bulletins, serial issues, other printed matter, audio and video recordings and transcripts of interviews, and slides. A portion of the collection was used as research material for Leslie Gottesman's book, To Fight and Learn: The Praxis and Promise of Literacy in Eritrea’s War of Independence (Red Sea Press, Lawrenceville, New Jersey, 1998).
Related Collection(s)
David D. Laitin papers
Paul Henze papers
Eritrean subject collection
Ethopian subject collection
Education--Eritrea.; Eritrea--History--Revolution, 1962-1993.; Eritrea--History.
- Biographical File, 1993
  - Entry visa application, 1993 (Box-folder 1: 1)
- Speeches and Writings, 1993-2003 (Box-folder 1: 2)
- Office File, 1993 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Receipts, 1993
- Correspondence, 1983-2010
  - Abraha, Michael, 1996 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Africa Solidarity Committee, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Albaugh, Erika, 2005 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Asfaha, Yonas Mesfun, undated (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Bjorndal, Jon, 1999 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - Brief report from Eritrea, 1997-2005 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - Checole, Kassahun, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Eritreans for Peace and Democracy, 1992 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - Gebreselassie, Beraki, 1991-1994 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - Gebreyesus, Elsa, 1993-2003 (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - Gebrezgheir, Elias A., 1995-1996 (Box-folder 1: 14)
  - Ghebrehiwet, Hagos, 1992 (Box-folder 1: 15)
  - Ghebrehiwet, 2001 (Box-folder 1: 16)
  - Ghebretensae, Woldemichael, 1993 (Box-folder 1: 17)
  - GK, Melku, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 1: 18)
  - Global Discount Travel, 1996 (Box-folder 1: 19)
  - Goitom, Abrehet, 2004 (Box-folder 1: 20)
  - Hailemariam, Chefena, 2002 (Box-folder 1: 21)
  - Hailemariam, Petros, 1999-2002 (Box-folder 1: 22)
  - Hailu, Dawit H., undated (Box-folder 1: 23)
  - Harris, Paul L., 2008 (Box-folder 1: 24)
  - Hauser, Karen A., 1992-1997 (Box-folder 1: 25)
  - Highfield, Paul, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 1: 26)
  - Imam, Ahmed M., 2003 (Box-folder 1: 27)
  - Irwin, Bob, 1993 (Box-folder 1: 28)
  - Iyob, Salome, 1993-2003 (Box-folder 1: 29)
  - Jones, Scott, 1992 (Box-folder 1: 30)
  - Juris, Jeff S., 2000 (Box-folder 1: 31)
  - Kessler, Laurie, 1993-2002 (Box-folder 1: 32)
  - Kessler, Wayne, 1993-2002 (Box-folder 1: 33)
  - Kidane, Nunu, 2000 (Box-folder 1: 34)
  - Kurvers, Jeanne, 2002 (Box-folder 1: 35)
  - Lee, Priscilla, 1995 (Box-folder 1: 36)
  - Legum, Josephine, 1994 (Box-folder 1: 37)
  - Marcos, Ayn Alem, 1993 (Box-folder 1: 38)
  - Mekonnen, Yemane, 2002 (Box-folder 1: 39)
  - Melles, Ghebrehiwot, 2001 (Box-folder 1: 40)
  - Mesghinna, Wolde, 1992 (Box-folder 1: 41)
  - Mockey, Kys, 1993 (Box-folder 1: 42)
  - Müller, Tanja R., 1999 (Box-folder 1: 43)
  - Nakazawa, Rika, 1996 (Box-folder 1: 44)
  - National Academy of Education, Washington, D.C., 2001 (Box-folder 1: 45)
  - National Union of Eritrean Women, 1992 (Box-folder 1: 46)
  - National Union of Eritrean Youth and Workers, 1992 (Box-folder 1: 47)
  - Negash, Almaz, 1996 (Box-folder 1: 48)
  - Provisional Government of Eritrea, 1993 (Box-folder 1: 49)
  - Research and Information Center on Eritrea, 1992 (Box-folder 1: 50)
  - Rosenbloom, Oscar, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 1: 51)
  - Seyoum, Tedros, 2001-2010 (Box-folder 1: 52)
  - Sister Thomas, 1993 (Box-folder 1: 53)
  - Stefanos, Asgedet, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 1: 54)
  - Tedros, Zecarias, 2003-2007 (Box-folder 1: 55)
  - Tesfagiorgis, Gebre, 1996 (Box-folder 1: 56)
  - Tesfamariam, Issayas, 1992-2000 (Box-folder 1: 57)
  - Travel Advisors, 1993 (Box-folder 1: 58)
  - Tsegai, Amen, 2003 (Box-folder 1: 59)
  - Tseggai, Araia, 1992 (Box-folder 1: 60)
  - University of Washington, Seattle, 2003 (Box-folder 1: 61)
  - Woldegiorgis, Andeberhan, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 1: 62)
  - Woldemichael, Solomon, 2000 (Box-folder 1: 63)
  - Woldu, Kidane, 1993 (Box-folder 1: 64)
  - Zerom, Kiflemariam, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 1: 65)
- Subject File, 1945-2011
  - "Against All Odds," Conference on African Languages and Literatures into the 21st Century, Asmara, Eritrea, 2000 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Africa Events, 1985 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - Africa: Journal of the International African Institute, 1992 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - Africa Report, 1987-1993 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - Africa Today, 1990-1993 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - African Affairs, 1981-1992 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - African Studies Association (ASA), 1996-2005 (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - Anti-Slavery Society Human Rights Series Report #3, 1980, "Eritrea: The Longest War" by David Pool (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - All Africa.com, 2003 (Box-folder 2: 9)
  - Azania, vol. XXVI, 1992 (Box-folder 2: 10)
  - Bibliographies, undated (Box-folder 2: 11)
  - Bibliography (Eritrea), 1945-1999 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - "Birth of a Nation," press clippings and commentaries on the Eritrean Referendum and the Declaration of Independence, 1993 (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - Center of Afro-American and African Studies; Higher and Adult Continuing Education, 1984 (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - The Corporate Council on Africa, "Pharmaceuticals and Drugs Opportunities in Eritrea,", 1996 (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - "The Creation and Termination of the Ethio-Eritrean Federation and the Rise of Eritrea to National Revolution: A Dissertation," by Ogbazghi, Yohannes, 1986 (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - Development, Eritrea, 1953, 1991-2000
    - "Rural Reconstruction in Action: Experience in the Near and Middle East," by Allen, H.B., 1953 (Box-folder 3: 6)
    - "Eritrea: A New Country Emerges," by Connell, Dan, 1992 (Box-folder 3: 7)
    - Insights, "Grassroots International," volume 7, number 1, 1993 (Box-folder 3: 8)
    - "Restoration of Endangered Woodlands in Eritrea, N.E. Africa," by Jones, Scott, undated (Box-folder 3: 9)
    - News items and newspaper clippings, 1991-2000 (Box-folder 3: 10)
    - USAID, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 3: 11)
    - "Education in Eritrea," by Woldemariam, Mehari, 1997 (Box-folder 3: 12)
  - Education and development, 1974-2004
    - "The Experience of the Elimu Association of Zaire," by Bakumba, Nteba, and Bukuru Katana, 1991 (Box-folder 4: 1)
    - "The Socioeconomic Impact of Schooling in a Developing Country," by Behrman, Jere R. and Barbara L. Wolfe, 1984 (Box-folder 4: 2)
    - "Knowledge for the Masses: World Models and National Curricula, 1920-1986," by Benavot, Aaron, 1991 (Box-folder 4: 3)
    - "Participatory Development Demands Participatory Training," by Bhasin, Kamla, 1991 (Box-folder 4: 4)
    - "International Outreach for Adult Learners in Local Organizations," by Bolton, Elizabeth B., 1989 (Box-folder 4: 5)
    - "The Impact of Culture on Cognition," by Broasu, Thomas J., 1990 (Box-folder 4: 6)
    - "Education as Social Invention," by Bruner, Jerome S., 1983 (Box-folder 4: 7)
    - "Traditional Adult Education in Kenya: Some Thoughts for Today's World," by Cassara, Beverley B. and George N. Reche, 1990 (Box-folder 4: 8)
    - "Educating Science and Technology: Teachers for Rural Development," by Chaytor, Daniel E. B., 1987 (Box-folder 4: 9)
    - "Education and Socioeconomic Development in Africa: The Search for the Missing Link," by Court, David, 1987 (Box-folder 4: 10)
    - "Regenerating African Land: Can Reading Contribute?," by Dianzungu, D.B., 1991 (Box-folder 4: 11)
    - "Adult Literacy in Rural Areas," by Ferrel, Susan T. and Aimee Howley, 1991 (Box-folder 4: 12)
    - "Help for Basic Education in Africa: What Donors Can Do," by Hartwell, Ash, 1987 (Box-folder 4: 13)
    - "Producing Textbooks in Developing Countries," by Heyneman, Stephan P., 1990 (Box-folder 4: 14)
    - "Human Rights and the Liberation Struggle: The Importance of Creative Tension," by Houser, George M., 1992 (Box-folder 4: 15)
    - "Convergent and Divergent Trends in National Educational Systems," by Inkeles, Alex and Larry Sirowy, 1983 (Box-folder 4: 16)
    - "The Effects of Liberation from Illiteracy on the Lives of 31 Women: A Case Study," by Junge, Barbara J. and Debebe Tegegne, 1985 (Box-folder 4: 17)
    - "Local Lessons from Abroad: Adult Learning," by Knox, Allen B., 1990 (Box-folder 4: 18)
    - "Education Reform when Nations Undergo Radical Political and Social Transformation," by Labelle, Thomas J. and Christopher R. Ward, 1990 (Box-folder 4: 19)
    - "Forms of Decentralization and Their Implication for Education," by Lauglo, Jon, 1995 (Box-folder 4: 20)
    - "A New Life Is Being Built: Liberation Support Movement,", 1974 (Box-folder 4: 21)
    - "Mobilizing Women for Literacy," by Lind, Agneta, 1990 (Box-folder 4: 22)
    - "Adult Basic Education in Rural Development Projects: A Micro-Level Case Study," by Lyster, Elda, 1991 (Box-folder 4: 23)
    - "The Education of Adult Refugees in Somalia," by Macharia, David, 1990 (Box-folder 4: 24)
    - "The Ugandan Literacy Experience," by Manjanja-Zaali, I.M., 1991 (Box-folder 4: 25)
    - "Literacy and Adult Education in the Occupied Territories," by Mani, Suha, 1991 (Box-folder 4: 26)
    - "America and Africa: A Comparative Study in Educational Philosophy," by Marrah, John K., 1989 (Box-folder 4: 27)
    - "Africa and the West: News Tools for Old," by Mazrui, Ali A., 1987 (Box-folder 4: 28)
    - "Can Agriculture be a Key to African Development?," by McBreen, Edna, 1987 (Box-folder 4: 29)
    - News items and newspaper clippings, 1990-2004 (Box-folder 4: 30)
    - "Hot Literacy in Cold Societies: A Comparative Study of the Sacred Value of Writing," by Niezen, R. W., 1991 (Box-folder 4: 31)
    - "Rolling Back the Desert with Bare Hands," by Pradervand, Pierre, 1987 (Box-folder 4: 32)
    - "Women and Literacy: A Quest for Justice," by Ramdas, Lalita, 1990 (Box-folder 4: 33)
    - "Eritrean Education: Historical Perspective," by Rena, Ravinder, 2003 (Box-folder 4: 34)
    - "Contingency Planning for Innovative Projects: Designing Education Reforms in Developing Countries," by Rondinelli, Dennis A., 1989 (Box-folder 4: 35)
    - "Teacher Education for Women in Rural Development," by Sherman, Mary Antoinette Brown, 1987 (Box-folder 4: 36)
    - "Engendering Literacies: Adult Literacy Work and Changing Gender Identities in a Chinese Village (Draft)," by Stites, Regie, 1995 (Box-folder 4: 37)
    - "The Attitudes of Grade Seven and Eight English Teachers Towards English by TV Programs," by Tewelde, Yacob, 1990 (Box-folder 4: 38)
    - "Education for Rural Development: Introduction," by Tlou, Josiah and Hubert Dyasi, 1987 (Box-folder 4: 39)
    - "One Billion Illiterates: A Challenge for our Time," UNESCO Courier, 1990 (Box-folder 4: 40)
    - "Educational Development: Priorities for the Nineties," by Verspoor, Adriaan, 1990 (Box-folder 4: 41)
    - World Bank: Eritrea, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 4: 42)
    - "Studying Innovations in Education: Internationalization of Approaches," by Zakharieva, Mariana, 1991 (Box-folder 4: 43)
  - Education, 1996-1999
    - "A Hateful Fate," by Melles, Amanuel, 1996 (Box-folder 5: 1)
    - "The Unread Letters," Parts 1-4, by Mengesha, T. Sium, 1996 (Box-folder 5: 2)
    - "History of Education, Printing, and Literacy in Ethiopia," by Pankhurst, Rickard, 1998 (Box-folder 5: 3)
    - "Promises and Obstacles in Eritrea's Education System," by Rude, John C., 1997 (Box-folder 5: 4)
    - News items, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - "Eritrean Theater: From the Front Lines to the Footlights," by Fitzpatrick, Leo, u ndated (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - Foreign Policy, "In Focus,", 1997 (Box-folder 5: 7)
  - Horn of Africa Bulletin, 1993 (Box-folder 5: 8)
  - Horn Review, 1991 (Box-folder 5: 9)
  - International Association of Universities/ International Center on Higher Education, 2000 (Box-folder 5: 10)
  - International Studies Association, "Civic and Ethnic Allegiances: Competing Visions of Nationalist Discourse in the Horn of Africa," by Garcetti, Eric, 1999 (Box-folder 5: 11)
  - "Italian Colonialism in Eritrea, 1882-1941: Policies, Praxis, and Impact," by Negash, Tekeste, 1987 (Box-folder 5: 12)
  - Eritrean Studies Association, 1992-2001 (Box-folder 5: 13)
  - Eritrean Studies Review, 1996 (Box-folder 5: 14)
  - Eritrea-Ethiopian Border War, 1998-2000
    - Amnesty International, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 5: 15)
    - Citizens for Peace, "The Uprooted," Parts 1 and 2, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 5: 16)
    - Eritrean Action Network for Peace (EANP), 2000 (Box-folder 5: 17)
    - Eritrean-American Community in South Bay, 2000 (Box-folder 5: 18)
    - Eritreans Living in the Bay Area, 1998 (Box-folder 5: 19)
    - "Genesis of the Border War," "The Price of a Bungled Peace-Making Approach," by Fessehazion, Tekie, 1998 (Box-folder 5: 20)
    - News items and newspaper clippings, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 5: 21)
    - Norwegian Refugee Council, 2000 (Box-folder 5: 22)
    - "The March of Folly" Re-enacted: A personal view," by Tesfai, Alemseged, 1998 (Box-folder 5: 23)
    - United Nations High Commission for Human Rights (UNHCR), 1998 (Box-folder 5: 24)
    - US-Eritrean Peoples' Friendship Association, 2000 (Box-folder 5: 25)
  - Eritrea Science Project, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 5: 26)
  - Eritrean Medical Journal, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 5: 27)
  - "The Eritrean Revolution and Contemporary World Politics," #2 by Petras, James, undated (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - Foreign Affairs, recent books, Eritrea: A Power in World Politics, 1991 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - Harvard Educational Review, "Women and Education in Eritrea: A Historical and Contemporary Analysis," by Stefanos, Asgedet, 1997 (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - Journal of African History, 1977-1992 (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - Journal of Eritrean Studies (JES), 1986-2002 (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - The Journal of Modern African Studies, 1987-2004 (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - Journal of Multilingual Multicultural Development, vol. 20:6, 1999 (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - Language in Africa with Linguistics, "Dialectical Variation and Intelligibility Levels Between the Dialects of the Tigre Language," by Idris, Saleh Mahmud, 1999 (Box-folder 6: 8)
  - Liberation Support Movement (LSM), LSM News, Winter, 1978 (Box-folder 6: 9)
  - The Middle East Journal, vol. 46, no. 1, 1992 (Box-folder 6: 10)
  - Ministry (Department) of Education (Eritrea), 1991-2011 (Box-folder 6: 11)
  - Monthly Review, 1993 (Box-folder 6: 12)
  - Nations and Nationalism, "Narratives of Nationalism in Eritrea: Research and Revisionism," by Dorman, Sara Rich, 2005 (Box-folder 6: 13)
  - Natural History, 1993 (Box-folder 6: 14)
  - New African, 2001 (Box-folder 6: 15)
  - The Personal and Guidance Journal, 1983 (Box-folder 6: 16)
  - Problems of Communism, 1990 (Box-folder 6: 17)
  - Proceedings of the First International Conference on Health in Eritrea, Milan, 1986 (Box-folder 6: 18)
  - Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Health in Eritrea, 1988 (Box-folder 6: 19)
  - Proceedings of the First Symposium in the US on Health in Eritrea, 1987 (Box-folder 6: 20)
  - Ravinder Renas: A Comprehensive History of Eritrea, 2006 (Box-folder 7 :1)
  - Regional Center for Human Rights and Development (Asmara, Eritrea), 1992-1994 (Box-folder 7 :2)
  - Research and Information Center on Eritrea (RICE), 1980-1982 (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - Research questions, undated
    - Education students, undated (Box-folder 7: 5)
    - Demoz, Berhane, undated (Box-folder 7: 4)
    - Ghebrai, Illen, undated (Box-folder 7: 6)
    - Kessler, Wayne and Laurie, undated (Box-folder 7: 7)
    - Memher, Asafa, undated (Box-folder 7: 8)
    - General, undated (Box-folder 7: 9)
  - Scandinavian Journal of Educational Research, 1995 (Box-folder 7: 10)
  - Social Science and Medicine, 1989 (Box-folder 7: 11)
  - Third World Conference, 1997 (Box-folder 7: 12)
  - Transcripts of conversations, 1992-1993, 1999-2001
    - Eritrea (1 compact disc), 1993 (Box-folder 7: 13)
    - Ephrem, Immouna, 1999 (Box-folder 7: 14)
    - Gebrekristos, Temesgen, 2001 (Box-folder 7: 15)
    - Ghebretensae, Woldemichael, 1993 (Box-folder 7: 16)
    - Hauser, Karen, 1992 (Box-folder 7: 17)
    - Iyob, Mehret, 2001 (Box-folder 7: 18)
    - Lijam, Senait, 1993 (Box-folder 7: 19)
    - Kahsai, Asfaha, 2001 (Box-folder 7: 20)
    - Negassi, Leteyesus and Lijam, Senait, 1993 (Box-folder 7: 21)
    - Tedros, Zecarias, 2001 (Box-folder 8: 1)
    - Temesgen, Hertema, 2001 (Box-folder 8: 2)
    - Tesfagiorgis, Abeda, undated (Box-folder 8: 3)
    - Ugubeab, Paulos, 2001 (Box-folder 8: 4)
  - United Nations Educational and Scientific Organization (UNESCO), "Principles and General Objectives of Education: Eritrea,", 2000 (Box-folder 8: 5)
  - United Nations International Children's Emergency Fund (UNICEF), "State of Eritrea's Children,", 1995 (Box-folder 8: 6)
  - University of Asmara, 1987-2002 (Box-folder 8: 7)
  - University of Asmara Students Association (UASA) Newsletter, 1993 (Box-folder 8: 8)
  - World AIDS, undated (Box-folder 8: 9)
  - World politics, 1991 (Box-folder 8: 10)
  - The World Today, 1991 (Box-folder 8: 11)
- Printed Matter, 1935-2007
  - Asmara International Community Center, undated (Box-folder 8: 12)
  - Association of Eritrean Students in North America (AESNA), 1978-1980 (Box-folder 8: 13)
  - The Atlantic Monthly, 1988 (Box-folder 8: 14)
  - Books for Eritrea, undated (Box-folder 8: 15)
  - The British Council Eritrea, undated (Box-folder 8: 16)
  - Business cards, undated (Box-folder 8: 17)
  - Catholic Institute for International Relations, undated (Box-folder 8: 18)
  - Chronicle of Higher Education, 2001 (Box-folder 8: 19)
  - The Cinema Guild, "Eritrean Artists in War and Peace,", 1997 (Box-folder 8: 20)
  - Coleman's African Studies Center (UCLA), undated (Box-folder 8: 21)
  - Community Development Society of America, 1989 (Box-folder 8: 22)
  - Compare, "Educational Development in Eritrea," by Hough, J. R., 1987 (Box-folder 8: 23)
  - Comparative and International Education Society, "Adult Literacy for Development in Ethiopia: A Review of Policy and Performance at Midpoint,", 1987 (Box-folder 8: 24)
  - The Constitution of Eritrea, 1997 (Box-folder 8: 25)
  - Corporate Council on Africa, undated (Box-folder 8: 26)
  - Direct Relief International, 1985 (Box-folder 8: 27)
  - Embassy of Eritrea, "Statement by HE Mr. Isaias Afeverki," Information on the Government of Eritrea, Links and Embassies of Eritrea, 1993 (Box-folder 8: 28)
  - Embassy of Ethiopia, "News from Ethiopia,", 1992 (Box-folder 8: 29)
  - Eritrea Alhaditha (New Eritrea) Arabic, 1993 (Box-folder 8: 30)
  - Eritrea Material Aid Campaign (EMAC), 1981-1984 (Box-folder 8: 31)
  - Eritrean Community Center, Inc., 1986 (Box-folder 8: 32)
  - Eritrea Profile, 1994-2001
    - Vol. 1, #16-42, 1994 (Box-folder 8: 33)
    - Vol. 2, #3-24, 1995 (Box-folder 9: 1)
    - Vol. 5, #34, 1998 (Box-folder 9: 2)
    - Vol. 5, #43- Vol. 6, #16, 1999 (Box-folder 9: 3)
    - Vol. 6, #17-42, 1999 (Box-folder 9: 4)
    - Vol. 6, #43- Vol. 7, #16, 2000 (Box-folder 9: 5)
    - Vol. 7, #17-43, 2000 (Box-folder 10: 1)
    - Vol. 7, #44- Vol. 8, #9, 2001 (Box-folder 10: 2)
  - Eritrea Quarterly, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 10: 3)
  - Eritrean Medical Association (EMA), Medical Support Committee for Eritrea, 1983 (Box-folder 10: 4)
  - Eritrean Peoples' Liberation Front (EPLF), 1977-1991
    - Central Bureau for Foreign Relations, 1977-1990 (Box-folder 10: 5)
    - European Office, Vol. 2, #2, undated (Box-folder 10: 6)
    - Information Department, "Dimtsi Hafash," biweekly newsletter, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 10: 7)
    - National Democratic Program, 1977 (Box-folder 10: 8)
    - National Guidance Department, undated (Box-folder 11: 1)
    - Press releases, 1978-1991 (Box-folder 11: 2)
    - Self Reliance... Only Way to Victory, undated (Box-folder 11: 3)
  - Eritrean Relief Association (ERA), 1987-1991 (Box-folder 11: 4)
  - Eritrean Relief Association Canada (ERAC), ERAC Educational Series 1-3, undated (Box-folder 11: 5)
  - Eritrean Relief Committee (ERC), 1983-1992 (Box-folder 11: 6)
  - Eritreans for Liberation in North Africa (ELNA), "Revolution in Eritrea,", 1975 (Box-folder 11: 7)
  - The Ethiopia Observer, 1992 (Box-folder 11: 8)
  - "Expo" in Tigrigna, by Almedom, Mesghina, undated (Box-folder 11: 9)
  - Film, "Eritrea: A Portrait of the Eritrean People, Their Struggle, and Their Will to Survive," by Kalesh, Susan, 1990 (Box-folder 11: 10)
  - Film, "White Hotel: A Documentary" by Solvang Tobi and Dianne Griffin, 1993 (Box-folder 11: 11)
  - "Fitewrari/ Vanguard" (Tigrigna), "On the 25th Anniversary of the Foundation of the Revolutionary School,", 2001 (Box-folder 11: 12)
  - Hadas Eritrea (New Eritrea), 2nd Year, #55, 67, 1993 (Box-folder 11: 13)
  - International Bureau of Education, "Ethiopia: The Role of Literacy Instructors in Changing Attitudes,", 1990 (Box-folder 11: 14)
  - International Institute for Educational Planning, "Training of Local-Level Administrative Personnel in National Literacy Programs,", 1982 (Box-folder 11: 15)
  - Middle East Research and Information Project (MERIP), #62, 1977 (Box-folder 11: 16)
  - Minorities Rights Group, "Voices from Eritrea," by Warner, Rachel, undated (Box-folder 11: 17)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box-folder 11: 18)
  - National Council of the Churches of Christ in the USA, "Monday: A Biweekly Newsletter on Refugees and Immigration Issues,", 1995 (Box-folder 11: 19)